A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The role of U.S. foundations in East-Central Europe (Reports 012072), 1991 (Box 564)
  15 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Europe, Eastern -- Congresses; Endowments -- Europe, Central -- Congresses; Technical assistance -- Europe, Eastern -- Congresses; Technical assistance -- Europe, Central -- Congresses; Pew Charitable Trusts; Rockefeller Brothers Fund
- Effective private sector contribution to development in Sub-Saharan Africa: conference papers (Reports 012073), 1986 (Box 564)
  Contains 13 papers covering four areas of interest: I. The relationships of governments and business (African governments' attitudes toward business and businesses' attitudes towards enhancing their contribution to African development. II. The relationshi
  Rural Poverty and Resources
  08650491
  v. (various pagings) + 3 pamphlets.
  Enabling Environment Conference (1986 Oct. 21-24: Kenyatta International Conference Centre)
  Economic development -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses; Investments, Foreign -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses; Business enterprises -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Congresses
- Conference on Women and Development (1976 June 2-6: Wellesley College): Conference papers 53 volumes. (Reports 012074) (Box 564-566)
  Contains reports presented at a conference on women and development held June 2-6, 1976 at Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass. Conference was sponsored by the Center for Research on Women in Higher Education and the Professions, Wellesley College;the Afri
  International Division/Office of the Vice President
  07550658
  2 archives boxes (10 linear in. containing 53 items).
  Women and national development: the complexities of change
  Conference on Women and Development (1976 June 2-6: Wellesley College)
  Women -- Employment -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Women in community development -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Women's rights -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Ford Foundation
- International Urbanization Survey: findings and recommendations (Reports 012075), 1972 (Box 566)
  07090524
  Survey of urbanization problems in developing countries.
  54 p.
  Urbanization -- Research -- Developing countries; City planning -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Division; Ford Foundation. Office of the Vice President
- Urbanization in Pakistan 1972? (Reports 012076) (Box 566)
  123, [11] leaves.
  Urbanization -- Research -- Pakistan; City planning -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation. Field Office Islamabad; Ford Foundation Asia and the Pacific Program development
- Urbanization in Argentina 1972? (Reports 012077) (Box 566)
  Urbanization -- Research -- Argentina; City planning -- Argentina; Ford Foundation. Field Office Rio de Janeiro; Ford Foundation Latin America and Caribbean Program development
- Concept paper on a national foundation for India: prepared for the Working Group on the National Foundation project, 25 Mar. (Reports 012078), 1991 (Box 566)
  Paper presented by Dr. M. S. Swaminathan, a Ford Foundation trustee, at the March 1991 meeting of the Board of Trustees, Lotos Club, New York City, March 27, 1991.
  Board of Trustees;Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Civil society -- India; Economic development -- India; Leadership -- India; Charities -- India; Ford Foundation India -- Program development; National Foundation for India
- Some questions for discussion in planning evaluation of great cities gray areas projects: meeting of project directors, May 26 (Reports 012079), 1960 (Box 566)
  Covers Great Cities/Gray Areas projects in Cleveland, Detroit, Milwaukee, Philadelphia, Pittsburgh and St. Louis. These projects were sponsored by the Foundation's program in Public Affairs. This report does not include answers to the questions or notes o
  Public Affairs
  Urban renewal -- United States; Urban schools -- United States; Ford Foundation. Great Cities; Ford Foundation. Gray Areas
- The TV-Radio Workshop, 1955 May 26. (Reports 012080) (Box 566)
  Prepared for the May 1955 meeting of the Board of Trustees. Includes the following recommended action: 1) Exhibit "1" - Extract from Supplement to Program Docket, Trustees' Meeting, March 4-5, 1955;2) Exhibit "2" - Report on Existing Organizations as Poss
  Board of Trustees;TV-Radio Workshop
  Educational broadcasting -- United States; Ford Foundation. TV-Radio Workshop
- Summary of comments of Seweryn Bialer (Reports 012081), 1988 (Box 567)
  Memo to Soviet-Eastern Europe Study Group, dated September 30, 1988.
  5 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Political science -- Soviet Union; Political science -- Europe, Eastern; World politics; Ford Foundation. International Affairs; Ford Foundation
- Fellowships and senior lawyers: Viable pro bono adjuncts?, 1990 Dec.: A report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 012082), 1991 (Box 567)
  Report discusses the ways in which law firms may assist the pro bono effort other than through the personal service of their members. Two concepts are discussed: 1) fellowships and 2) engaging retired or soon-to-be-retired senior lawyers.
  Legal assistance to the poor -- United States
- Toward justice: Foundation programs in human rights and social justice and governance and public policy in the Philippines: a program strategy paper (Reports 012084), 1991 (Box 567)
  Outlines program in public interest law and civic participation to enable disadvantaged groups in the Philippines to use legal processes and democratic institutions.
  47 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Public interest law -- Philippines; Legal assistance to the poor -- Philippines; Political participation -- Philippines; Human rights -- Philippines; Social justice -- Philippines; Civil society -- Philippines; Political planning -- Philippines; Ford Foundation Human Rights and Governance; Ford Foundation. Southeast Asia office
- Patterns of cooperation among grantmakers (Reports 012085), 1991 (Box 567)
  Program Division/Office of the Vice President
  09051448
  Council on Foundations, Inc.
  Support for a report on lessons learned about donor collaboration.
  v, 47 p. -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- International cooperation; Ford Foundation. Office of the Vice President; Council on Foundations; Council on Foundations, Inc.
- Report to the Ford Foundation on graduate programs in applied economics and public policy in Chile and Argentina, 1990 Oct. (Reports 012086) (Box 567)
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Argentia and the Southern Cone
  Economics -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Argentina; Economics -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Chile; Public policy (Law) -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Chile; Public policy (Law) -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Argentina; Policy sciences
- Proposed resolution and amendments to Ford Foundation retirement and thrift plans (Reports 012088), 1985 (Box 567)
  Resolution incorporating amendments required by the Employee Retirement Income Security of 1974 ... the Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982, the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 and the Retirement Equity Act of 1984."
  Personnel;Board of Trustees
  5 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Officials and employees -- Pensions; Ford Foundation
- Interim report to the advisory committee on International Training and Research, 1956 June. (Reports 012089) (Box 567)
  Prepared for the June 1956 meeting of the Board of Trustees. Includes an overview of ITR fellowship program, ITR items approved at the June Trustees meeting, a paper entitled, "Report on Conference on Undergraduate Teaching of International Studies" by R.
  International Training and Research;Board of Trustees
  Foreign study -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; International relations -- Study and teaching (Higher); Ford Foundation. Foreign Area Training Fellowship Program; Ford Foundation. International Training and Research ITR
- Facilitating economic and professional exchanges with Vietnam (Reports 012090), 1981 (Box 567)
  Memorandum to Franklin Thomas. Recommends Ford Foundation support for modest program to facilitate contacts between Vietnamese social scientists and colleagues elsewhere in Southeast Asia. Also contains Geithner's trip notes for his Nov. 1980 visit to Vie
  Social scientists -- Vietnam; Educational exchanges -- Asia, Southeastern
- Minority arts and culture study (Reports 012091), 1984 (Box 567)
  The purpose of this study was to enable the Education and Culture program to "gain an accurate sense of the attitudes and perceived needs of minority artistic and cultural groups." -p. 1.
  Minorities in art -- United States; Minority arts facilities -- United States; Ford Foundation. Education and Culture
- Report and recommendations 1972? (Reports 012092) (Box 567)
  Reviews the structure for administering the Foreign Area Fellowship Program (FAFP). In 1962, the Foundation had transferred the responsibility for administering its fellowship programs in foreign area studies to joint administration by the Social Science
  Foreign study -- Research; Foreign study -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Joint Committee on the Foreign Area Fellowship Program Reorganization; American Council of Learned Societies; Social Science Research Council
- Summary guides for the use of Ensminger, Moyer and Howard in India and Pakistan (Reports 012093), 1951 (Box 567)
  These guides concerning initial Foundation programs in India and Pakistan are intended to provide a record of present thinking which has resulted from the recent visits of Mr. Hoffman and other Foundation representatives to these countries. --p.1.
  Overseas Division;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  13 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- India; Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Ford Foundation India -- Program development; Ford Foundation
- Conference proceedings (Reports 012094), 1982 (Box 567)
  Contains conference reports by the following authors: Steven E. Miller, B.S. Zen Ruffinen, Peter Foot, Janice M. Hinton, Syed Javed Maswood and Neil Joeck. Also includes a cover memorandum, a tentative agenda and a note on the schedule.
  Developing Countries Program/International Affairs;United States and International Affairs Program/International Affairs
  08250504
  9 items (ca. 1 linear in.).
  Potential West European contributions to Alliance Forces for deterrence and power-projection in South-West Asia;Cold war in the cold: Soviet-American naval rivalry in NATO's northern flank;Energy security: the case of oil in Switzerland;Sale of FX aircr
  Conference of Ford-Funded Centers of International Security and Arms Control (1982 Jan. 21-22: Rand Graduate Institute, Santa Monica, Calif.)
  Arms control; Security, International; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- Possible Ford Foundation work in international security/international relations in Asia (Reports 012095), 1980 (Box 567)
  Memorandum to David E. Bell, Francis X. Sutton, John Bresnan and all Asian field offices. Includes an additional cover memorandum to Sutton discussing funding technicalities.
  [1], 22 leaves.
  Security, International -- Research; Arms control -- Research; Ford Foundation Asia
- Ford Foundation Urban Community College Transfer Opportunities Program: An evaluation of Phase I TOP projects in 24 urban community colleges, 1984 May 18 A report to the Office of Education and Culture, Ford Foundation (Reports 012096) (Box 567)
  Evaluates participants in Phase I of the Urban Community College Transfer Opportunities Program (UCCTOP) in order to select those institutions to be considered for continuing support in Phase II. Based on site visits by a panel of eight consultants. The p
  40, [60] leaves.
  Community colleges -- United States -- Evaluation; Minority college students -- United States -- Transfer; Community college students -- United States -- Transfer; Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; Ford Foundation. Urban Community College Transfer Opportunities Program UCCTOP; Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program development
- Papers presented to the conference Honduras: an international dialogue (Reports 012097-001), 1984
  8550023
  5 v.;var. pag. -- 28 cm.
  Conference Honduras, an International Dialogue (1984: Miami, Fla.)
  Political science -- Honduras; National security -- Honduras; International relations; Democracy -- Honduras; Human rights -- Honduras; Social justice -- Honduras; Economic development -- Honduras; Conference Honduras, an International Dialogue (1984: Miami, Fl; Florida International University. Latin American and Caribbean Center; Ford Foundation. Office for Mexico and Central America; Florida International University
- Evolucion reciente de la politica exterior y seguridad nacional de Honduras = Recent developments in foreign policy and national security in Honduras (Reports 012097-002), 1984 (Box 567)
  "Paper presented to the conference Honduras: an International Dialogue, Miami, November 29 to Devember 1, 1984." --T.p.
  08550023
  Florida International University
  Honduran participation in a U.S. conference on Honduras.
  Political science -- Honduras; National security -- Honduras; International relations; Democracy -- Honduras; Human rights -- Honduras; Social justice -- Honduras; Economic development -- Honduras; Florida International University. Latin American and Caribbean Center; Ford Foundation. Office for Mexico and Central America; Florida International University
- Problemas de la democracia en Honduras = Problems of democracy in Honduras (Reports 012097-003), 1984 (Box 567)
- Honduras: politica agricola y perspectivas = Honduras: agricultural policy and perspectives (Reports 012097-004), 1984 (Box 567)
- Los derrechos humanos y la justicia social en Honduras = Human rights and social justice in Honduras (Reports 012097-005), 1984 (Box 567)
- Honduras: desarrollo economico y productividad = Honduras: economic development and productivity (Reports 012097-006), 1984 (Box 567)
- The Black women oral history project: a guide to the transcripts (Reports 012098), 1987 (Box 568)
  08450736
  152 p.
  Afro-American women -- History -- Sources; Afro-American women -- Interviews; Oral history; Radcliffe College; Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America
- A partial assessment of the Foundation's external affirmative action policy (Reports 012099), 1986 (Box 568)
  Includes cover memorandum to Shep Forman discussing Yu's reservations about the report and 13 leaves of graphs representing his findings for the 11 organizations for which he gathered data. Yu profiled the representation of women and minorities on boards
  [1], 21 leaves: ill.
  Affirmative action programs -- United States; Ford Foundation Rules and practice
- Survey of Black and Hispanic art museums: A report to the Ford Foundation, 1987 Sept. (Reports 012100) (Box 568)
  Ruth Mayleas, program officer, Education and Culture, commissioned The Studio Museum in Harlem to conduct this survey--in the form of site visits--of the needs of Black and Hispanic fine arts museums in the United States.
  08600781
  36 leaves.
  Hispanic Americans -- Museums; African Americans -- Museums; Art museums -- United States; Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program development
- The bicentennial era: plans and opportunities, 1986 Sept. (Reports 012101) (Box 568)
  [2], 77 leaves.
  United States Constitution Bicentennial, 1987-1991; Education -- United States -- Aims and objectives; Ford Foundation Human Rights and Governance Program development
- A review of the National Foreign Language Center, 1991 (Reports 012102) (Box 568)
  Report prepared for Peter Stanley, Director of the Ford Foundation's Education and Culture Program, "as background to the Foundation's consideration of a request for additional funding from the Center." -p. 1. Submitted to Peter Stanley and Richard Lamber
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- United States; Johns Hopkins University. National Foreign Language Center
- Some reflections on the social sciences (Reports 012103), 1976 (Box 568)
  Memorandum from Craufurd Goodwin to David Bell, Vice President of the Ford Foundation's International Division, recording impressions on the "state of the social sciences in the United States." -p. 1.
  Social sciences -- United States
- Status report and strategy for the FY 86-87 biennium (Reports 012104), 1986 (Box 568)
  Memorandum to Susan V. Berresford, Barry Gaberman and Bernard McDonald.
  National service -- United States; Ford Foundation. National Service Task Force
- Some aspects of town and country planning in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-001), 1973 (Box 568)
  Bangladesh Field Office Reports
  City planning -- Bangladesh; Urbanization -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh
- Problems and prospects for rural development in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-002), 1973 (Box 568)
  Rural development -- Bangladesh
- A study of the needs and capacity for agro-economic planning and research in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-003), 1976 (Box 568)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Bangladesh; Agriculture and state -- Bangladesh; Bangladesh. Ministry of Agriculture and Forests
- Trip report and recommendations on cultural activities in Bangladesh, January 6-18, 1984, 1984 Jan. (Reports 012105-004) (Box 568)
  Archaeology -- Study and teaching -- Bangladesh; Folk music -- Study and teaching -- Bangladesh; Folk art -- Study and teaching -- Bangladesh; Theater -- Study and teaching -- Bangladesh
- BRAC Strategy for the 1990s: Observations and Recommendations (Reports 012105-005), 1987 (Box 568)
  Developing Countries Program/Bangladesh
  Bangladesh
- Health and Nutrition - Programme Opportunities for the Ford Foundation in Bangladesh: A Report to the Ford Foundation Dacca Office (Reports 012105-006), 1980 (Box 568)
- Ford Foundation Programs Related to Child Survival: A Review of Current and Future Prospects (Reports 012105-007), 1982 (Box 568)
- A Blue-print for Bangladesh Sterilization Programme (Reports 012105-008), 1977 (Box 568)
- A Review of Ford Foundation's Current and Future Programs in Rural Poverty and Resources in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-009), 1982 (Box 568)
- Returns to Scale to Family Size - Who Gains from High Fertility? (Reports 012105-010), 1979 (Box 568)
- The Social Sciences in the International Centre for Diarrheal Diseases, Bangladesh (Reports 012105-011), 1980 (Box 568)
- Behavioral Aspects of Health Research in Bangladesh - Needs and Possibilities. A Note Prepared for the Ford Foundation (Reports 012105-012), 1982 (Box 568)
- An Organizational Framework for Analytical Input in Formulation and Monitoring of Ford Policies in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-013), 1978 (Box 568)
- Women in Development: Final Consultancy Report, March 8-April 20 (Reports 012105-014), 1977 (Box 568)
- Comilla Revisited (Reports 012105-015), 1977 (Box 568)
- The Comilla Projects: A Personal Account (Reports 012105-016), 1974 (Box 568)
- Interim Report on the First Phase of Consultancy at the Bangladesh Academy for Rural Development: 16 March - 2 (Reports 012105-017), 1978 (Box 568)
- A Consultant Report on a Short Term Training for Local Scientists - ISRT (Reports 012105-018), 1977 (Box 568)
- A Consultant Report on KARIKA, Bangladesh Handicraft Coopera-Federation Ltd. (Reports 012105-019), 1976 (Box 568)
- Suggestions on Program Directions for the BKB (Reports 012105-020), 1977 (Box 568)
- A Consultant Report on PCFP Population Control and Family Planning Directorate, IEM Division (Reports 012105-021), 1978 (Box 569)
- Strengthening Economics at Dacca University: A Consultant Report (Reports 012105-022), 1978 (Box 569)
- A Consultant Report on COTA Civil Officers' Training Academy, Dacca, Bangladesh (Reports 012105-023), 1978 (Box 569)
- Upazila-Level Government in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-024), 1987 (Box 569)
- Evaluation of the Women's Desk of the Bangladesh Academy for Rural Development and the Ministry of Agriculture, Government of Bangladesh (Reports 012105-025), 1988 (Box 569)
- Report to the Ford Foundation, Dhaka, Bangladesh, on suggestions for investment in curricula development, research, education and training that combines sic social science and natural resource disciplines to alleviate rural poverty and to ensure resource conservation (Reports 012105-026), 1989 (Box 569)
  Rural development -- Bangladesh; Conservation of natural resources -- Bangladesh; Poverty -- Bangladesh
- Social forestry and the rural poor (Reports 012105-027), 1983 (Box 569)
  Social forestry programs -- Bangladesh; Forests and forestry -- Social aspects -- Bangladesh
- The Nature of Rural Class Differentiation in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-028), 1977 (Box 569)
- Irrigation assets for the rural landless (Reports 012105-029), 1981 (Box 569)
- Diary report: Consultancy to Dacca office to assist in reviewing status of landless irrigation programmes (Reports 012105-030), 1981 (Box 569)
- Diary report: Consultancy to MOA/GOB (Reports 012105-031), 1980 (Box 569)
- Bureaucratic reproduction under peripheral conditions (Reports 012105-032), 1981 (Box 569)
- How the interests of the rural poor can be included in the Second Five Year Plan (Reports 012105-033), 1980 (Box 569)
- Executive summary: How the interests of the rural poor can be included in the Second Five Year Plan (Reports 012105-034), 1980 (Box 569)
- Diary report: Consultancy with PROSHIKA to review and monitor second season of landless irrigation program (Reports 012105-035), 1982 (Box 569)
- The access problem and class formation: Some reflections on the Kosi development region (Reports 012105-036), 1979 (Box 569)
- Lateral thinking on BARD (Based on visit to BARD, Comilla, 5-6 (Reports 012105-037), 1980 (Box 569)
- The politics of rural development in Bangladesh: A study of class and power from a Comilla village (Reports 012105-038), undated (Box 569)
- Consultancy of Geoffrey D. Wood to Ministry of Agriculture and Forests, Government of Bangladesh (Reports 012105-039), 1979 (Box 569)
- Access to fertilizer distribution - A research suggestion (Reports 012105-040), undated (Box 569)
  Bangladesh; Caṭṭagrāma Bisvabidyālaẏa
- Diary report: Consultancy to Dacca office to develop format for evaluating landless water pump schemes (Reports 012105-041), 1981 (Box 569)
- Micro studies, employment and the strategies of development (Reports 012105-042), 1975 (Box 569)
  Bangladesh; Marga Institute
- Views on village studies research institution in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-043), 1975 (Box 569)
- Consultancy to the Bangladesh Ministry of Health (Reports 012105-044), 1976 (Box 569)
- The BRAC (Bangladesh Rural Advancement Committee) health care, preventative medicine and family planning services program (Reports 012105-045), undated (Box 569)
- Revised draft terms of reference (Reports 012105-046), 1976 (Box 569)
  Bangladesh; Bangladesh Agricultural Development Corporation (BADC)
- Consultancy to the Ministry of Agriculture (Bangladesh) (Reports 012105-047), 1978 (Box 570)
- Nutritional implications of agriculture price policy in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-048), 1980 (Box 570)
- Tenure, returns to scale and the efficiency of rice production in Bangladesh (Reports 012105-049), 1979 (Box 570)
- Tips on how to use the IBM 370 computer system at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (Reports 012105-050), 1980 (Box 570)
- Food policy and nutrition in Bangladesh (summary report on research project) (Reports 012105-051), 1979 (Box 570)
- Integrated household economic and expenditure survey 1976-1977: Instructions to field staff (Reports 012105-052) (Box 570)
  Bangladesh; Bangladesh Ministry of Planning, Statistics Division, Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics